Emilio Campos Jr.

Chicago, IL | (815) 543-8461 | ecampos.jr54@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

As a former lawyer, I managed over 60 cases at once and collaborated with multiple teams. I analyzed 500 pages of detailed information per case and researched case law to resolve issues. I applied these skills to develop applications in my software engineering boot camp: I collaborated with teams, analyzed problems, and researched to debug any issues. As a software engineer, I will continue to apply these problem-solving skills that were essential to my work as an attorney.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | MongoDB | Express | React | Node | Python | Flask | APIs OAuth | Passport.js | SQL | NoSQL | PostgreSQL | HTML | CSS | Tailwind CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Video Game Library | Code | App

- Designed a MERN-stack application to allow users to perform CRUD functionality on games
- Implemented an OAuth 2.0 authorization framework and Passport.js as the authentication middleware
- Utilized the fetch method to send HTTP methods to a third-party API to render data
- Connected this SPA using a MongoDB database to store information regarding each game
- Deployed app to Heroku using Git and managed Git repositories with GitHub

GitRipped | Code | App

- React single page application that contains preset exercises and allows users to customize their own
- Built the backend, including the model, view, and controller layers to organize data for each exercise
- Connected the application to a third-party REST API to import exercises and render data
- Created the UI components to show both custom and API exercises
- Extensively engaged in pair programming, debugging and version control best practices

Ollivanders | Code | App

- Utilized JavaScript, Mongoose, Express and EJS
- Implemented RESTful routes and full CRUD functionality to allow the user to view, edit and add custom wands
- Used the Models, Views and Controllers paradigm (MVC) to design and create templates for each product

Emilio's Blackjack | Code | App

- Applied CSS to HTML elements via extensive DOM manipulation
- Researched JavaScript loops and combined them with the push method to form the deck as an array

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Staff Attorney I | Catholic Charities Legal Assistance

06/2021 - 04/2022

- Identified legal problems of over 100 clients and communicated their resolution options to them
- Communicated with multiple opposing counsels to reach optimal case resolution for clients

Associate Attorney | Bryce Downey and Lenkov LLC

01/2021 - 06/2021

- Collaborated with multiple teams to execute case plan based on court deadlines and procedures
- Developed detailed legal strategy based on analysis of incident, medical treatment, and trial costs

Law Clerk | Bryce Downey and Lenkov LLC

01/2020 - 06/2020 & 10/2020 - 01/2021

Researched case law extensively and adapted findings to calculate damages and write court motions

EDUCATION

General Assembly Software Engineering Certification	11/2022
University of Illinois College of Law Juris Doctor	05/2020
Loyola University Chicago Bachelor of Business Administration in Economics and Business Management	05/2013